The world was watching in 1972 as 11 Israeli athletes were murdered at the
Munich Olympics. This is the story of what happened next.
Munich is a drama, action, history film directed by Steven Spielberg.
During the 1972 Olympic Games in Munich, eleven Israeli athletes are taken hostage and
murdered by a Palestinian terrorist group known as Black September.
In retaliation, the Israeli government recruits a group of Mossad agents to
track down and execute those responsible for the attack.
Avner, played by Eric Bana.
Steve, played by Daniel Craig.
Carl, played by Ciarán Hinds.
Robert, played by Mathieu Kassovitz.
Hans, played by Hanns Zischler.
Daphna, played by Ayelet Zurer.
Munich is a 2005 epic historical drama film produced and directed by
Steven Spielberg, co-written by Tony Kushner and Eric Roth.
It is based on the 1984 book Vengeance by George Jonas, an account of
Mossad assassinations following the Munich massacre.
Munich was released by Universal Pictures in the United States and Canada and internationally by DreamWorks Pictures on December 23, 2005,
and received five Oscar nominations: Best Picture, Best Director, Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Editing, and Best Score.
The film made $131 million worldwide but just $47 million in the United States,
making it one of Spielberg's lowest-grossing films domestically.
In 2017, the film was named the 16th "Best Film of the
21st Century So Far" by The New York Times.
The film explores themes of hotel room, israel,
mossad, assassination, paris, france.
The tone is emotional and intense.